the original Bitcoin community was in
Asia. You know, it was not the US. I
actually have a theory that I've
developed over the past like four years,
which is you tend to see the meta or the
narrative of the cycle that we're in
happen once in a small way in the cycle
before. You're going to see is all of
the best companies in the world adopting
a Bitcoin strategy to pour their profits
into Bitcoin. And you're going to see
the market reward that massively. That's
going to create this flywheel effect for
the Bitcoin price that will propel us to
orders of magnitude higher from where we
are right now. The S&P 500 and and some
of these indexes, you have to be a
profitable company in order to join.
They have not let Micro Strategy in up
until this point because of those
accounting rules because Micro Strategy
did not look like a profitable company.
Now that those accounting rules have
changed, Micro Strategy is a massively
profitable company and it's about to get
inducted into the S&P and that's going
to create massive amounts of passive
flows into Micro Strategy. That's going
to be a massive thing to watch. It
should happen soon. When that happens,
you will see billions of dollars flow
into Micro Strategy and therefore
Bitcoin due to no other reason than like
all of these passive funds have to
allocate to it.
Got the whole crypto world.
[Music]
If you want success, then take a look
away.
>> Today I'm super super excited to be
joined by Brandon Green. He is one of
the most important people behind the
scenes in Bitcoin. So he he's helped
grown Bitcoin conference into the best
global event now in places like
Amsterdam, Abu Dhabi, Hong Kong, and of
course US. He is also the chief of staff
to the CEO of BTC Inc. working directly
with the top team to shape the future of
Bitcoin. And he's smart, he's strategic,
he is one of the reasons why Bitcoin
events are so cool right now. Really
happy to have you here, Brandon. Yeah,
honored to be here and uh thank you for
that that glowing uh review of uh who I
am. I I don't know if I'll try to live
up to all of it.
>> Let's start with something really
interesting. Okay, so I was in Vegas um
for the Bitcoin conference in um May.
Yeah, it was in May. And
>> I've heard this really interesting
observation. So this year the female
toilets actually has a line and pre
people who's attended previous events
said it was always the male toilets
being packed and no females on site. So
is that a sign for bull or bare market?
>> I think it's probably a sign for
neither. I think this is a sign for
progress. you know, Bitcoin was really
born out of this cipher punk sort of uh
uh highly online uh subculture and we're
starting to see it really, you know,
it's almost cliche to say break into the
mainstream at this point. It is
mainstream and uh and so, you know,
where there's the greatest gains to be
seen in sort of the uh composition of
the Bitcoiner user base is with women.
Uh because, you know, there were so few
early on. uh now we're getting to to a
little closer to par and I think that's
awesome and and you know it's an
important step in the adoption cycle for
Bitcoin.
>> You've been in Bitcoin for a long time,
right?
>> Uh since 2017. Has the definition of
being a Bitcoin maxi changed for you? Or
you know how a normal person getting
into crypto first they learn about
Bitcoin and then there is this shinier
object was it which is one of the you
know alts or a memecoin that pumped I
don't know like 10x 100x in a week and
you're like oh that sounds cooler let me
just try and buy some of those. Have you
been
an altcoiner or shitcoiner they say?
>> Yeah, you know, uh uh it's funny. So
when I joined in 2017,
uh uh you know, Vitalic Buterine
actually used to write for Bitcoin
magazine and and uh I interfaced with
him a few times uh in my early kind of
time at at Bitcoin magazine. and I was I
was writing articles and um
>> he's the one who coined the term Bitcoin
maximalist and he used it in a
derogatory sense uh where you know
someone was kind of
>> um I don't remember the the full
conversation but it was someone who
wasn't that excited about Ethereum. this
was early days of Ethereum. Uh and
we're, you know, we're basically saying
like we should just devote all of our
focus to Bitcoin and he kind of uh
derided the person for being a Bitcoin
maximalist. Um and and so in the early
like the very beginnings of at least my
tenure in the space, uh being a Bitcoin
maximalist was seen as a negative thing.
uh you know it it hadn't quite really
played out yet uh to say like oh Bitcoin
for sure is going to be the uh uh king
cryptocurrency in our space and that was
something that really started to I think
form and articulate in that 2018 bare
market where you know you had this all
these ICOs all these shitcoins all of
these things launching through Ethereum
and uh they were all just hemorrhaging
value And the question was, you know,
where do you
invest not in a a bull market, but in a
bare market? What actually protects you
the most? And I think that's where
Bitcoin, you know, especially in 2018
really shined. I mean, even though it it
was down 75% 80% uh compared to 99% for
many of the projects, it it really was
the the safe haven of the space. And I
think growing out of that, uh, the
narratives really started to form around
why it's so important to have Bitcoin
quote unquote maximalism. And and really
what that means is just a recognition
that there's um a lot of different
cryptocurrency, altcoins, shitcoins
competing for other things other than
what Bitcoin is competing for for. And
what Bitcoin is competing for is the
decentralized monetary system of the
world. Um and and so in that way like it
needs to be set aside. Uh and then if
you want to talk about other things
happening in the cryptocurrency space
that you know to me that's okay. It's
not as interesting. It's okay to talk
about it. Uh uh it's it's just you know
it's not the same as talking about
Bitcoin. So that's that's how I've kind
of viewed it.
>> Okay. So here comes the next question.
You know how after strategy um they're
like, "Oh my god, this is the perfect
cheat sheet um the stock went crazy
after he uh Michael Sailor adopted the
Bitcoin strategy, right?" And then you
see Metaplanet and a lot of other
smaller Bitcoin companies so-called, but
a lot of them they are not really
Bitcoiners. They just see that adding
Bitcoin on their balance sheet put the
stock price. What is your view on those
companies?
>> Yeah, I I mean I think that um I think
that these Bitcoin treasury companies
are uh probably the most interesting
thing happening in the space right now.
And there's a there's a couple reasons
why. First of all, like I think this is
the narrative of the cycle. Um, you
know, I actually have a uh a theory that
I've developed over the past like four
years, which is
>> you tend to see the like the meta or the
narrative of the cycle that we're in
>> happen once like or like in a small way
in the cycle before. And so if you go
all the way back to um you know like the
>> uh was it the Mastercoin ICO and the
Ethereum ICO
>> that happened back in you know 2014ish.
Uh uh and then ICOs became the major uh
theme of 2017.
>> Um but also in 2017 there was this
little thing called CryptoKitties on
Ethereum which was the first ever NFT
project or at least the the first big
NFT project. Um, and of course NFTTS
became the the meta, I would say, of of
the 2021 cycle, right? Uh, but in 2020,
you saw this Michael Sailor guy launch a
Bitcoin treasury company. And I think
that Bitcoin treasury companies are the
meta of this cycle, this 2025, 2024,
2025, probably into 2026 cycle. And uh
you know my my bold prediction would be
that uh you've seen the US announce the
strategic reserve strategic bitcoin
reserve. I think nation state adoption
is going to be the the major meta of the
future cycle from now. So all that being
said you know like that's that's how I'm
framing you know bitcoin treasuries for
this cycle. But if we're looking at like
what's really going on, what you're
seeing is uh the market, the stock
market is rewarding c companies for uh
you know saving their money and valuing
their profits in Bitcoin. And it it's
not that like absurd or crazy of an
idea, but the thing is is the market is
so starved for that activity that you're
seeing wild premiums on it. And and so,
you know, you're seeing these companies
that are able to have a 2x uh some of
them are 10x MNAV, you know, uh 10x the
valuation of the Bitcoin they're holding
without an operating company to go
alongside them that really imbus them
any sort of value. And and so I think
we're in a moment in time right now
where this trade exists and you can
basically just arbitrage the, you know,
value of your stock versus the
underlying Bitcoin you have. I don't
think that's going to last forever.
uh um you know, maybe we've got a six
more months of that, maybe less, maybe
more, but but it's not going to last
forever. And what's going to take that
place is
>> publicly traded companies that have
massive profits that are dumping their
profits into Bitcoin and the market is
going to reward that behavior with the
premium on the stock. Uh and and that
will be the thing that that kind of
creates the the fastest horse, let's uh
let's say. And so what I think we're
going to see happen is not this
proliferation of holding company, you
know, treasury companies that don't do
anything except buy Bitcoin. Um, you
know, I think that that's mostly run its
course already. Uh, uh, you know, you'll
see it in some other markets, right,
internationally, but in terms of like
the major markets that all those plays
are already out there. Instead, what
you're going to see is all of the best
companies in the world adopting a
Bitcoin strategy uh to pour their
profits into Bitcoin. And you're going
to see the market reward that massively.
And uh that's going to create this
flywheel effect for the Bitcoin price
that will propel us to, I mean, orders
of magnitude higher from where we are
right now.
>> Do you predict it's going to happen this
cycle or next cycle?
>> It's a good question. I mean, it's it's
a matter of time in my mind. Uh I don't
think
if you had asked me three years ago I
would say okay we have major blockers
right number one uh uh institutions
still don't believe in Bitcoin. Well now
we have the Bitcoin ETFs Black Rockck's
all in uh uh you know Bridgewwaterat's
all in like
>> that's no longer an issue. Then I would
say you know we had these FASBY
accounting rules especially in the US
where you know on a on a public markets
balance sheet it didn't treat Bitcoin as
uh it treated as like an intangible
asset. So you couldn't market to market.
>> Uh uh which means that actually this
happened today with Micro Strategy. This
was the first time Micro Strategy was
actually allowed to realize the
appreciation on all their Bitcoin
they've been holding for the past 5
years, right? And so you know that was
something that was punishing public
companies and preventing them from
adopting. Uh and then you know the third
thing I would say is is uh uh you didn't
have a regulatory environment that felt
um supportive of of you know dipping
your toe into Bitcoin like this. Well,
now you've got regulatory regimes around
the world that are all finding you know
fighting tooth and nail. Uh the game
theory is flipped right now all of a
sudden they all want to be the place
where where the Bitcoin and crypto
companies can go. And so I think that if
you just combine those three things, um
it there are no barriers for this meme
to play out in the market now. So it's
it's really just a matter of it
continuing to propagate.
>> Would you expand more on the accounting
rule change because Michael Sailor was
talking about this last year, but we
want to know more details. How does that
benefit um more companies buying
Bitcoin?
>> Yeah, it's a good question. And and to
be clear, I'm not a CFO or an
accountant, so you know, some of this
stuff I I may butcher a little bit, but
the the way that public companies have
to run their books, uh, and therefore
like the way that they can, uh, uh,
record profit, record loss, um, you
know, report their finances to the
market is is something called, uh, uh,
GAP accounting. And uh and it's the the
FASBY, which is a um an accounting
regulatory apparatus that basically puts
these standards out there. And so uh a
while back they said Bitcoin is an
intangible asset. And so it should be
valued on your balance sheet basically
at the the value that you purchased it.
Uh with the exception that if it goes
down, you have to mark tomarket those
losses. So, uh, you know, if if Sailor
were to buy it at, you know, $10 and it
goes down to $5, he has to recognize on
that balance sheet. But if it goes to
$10 from $10 to $10 million, he can't
recognize that on his balance sheet,
which means things like access to
leverage, access to to, you know,
financing, um, you know, all sorts of uh
uh just having the market uh recognize
the the valuation of your company, like
the the book value of your company. It
it's not allowed. It's kind of like this
strange handcuff that existed for years.
Uh, and so that got lifted back in
January. Uh, and and it's going to cause
a lot of um a lot of companies that were
sitting on the sidelines to change their
mind. And I I'll tell you the one place
where it's like very clear uh that that
this change will have an impact, which
is um uh the S&P 500 and and some of
these indexes where you know you have to
uh uh be a profitable company in order
to join. They have not let Micro
Strategy in up until this point because
of those accounting rules because Micro
Strategy did not look like a profitable
company. Now that those accounting rules
have changed, Micro Strategy is a
massively profitable company and it's
about to get inducted into the S&P. Uh
and that's going to create massive
amounts of passive flows into Micro
Strategy uh that have never never come
in before. You know, think of all those
index funds, your Charles Schwabs, your
Vanguards, your your Black Rockcks,
anyone who just buys the S&P, you know,
buys this sort of passive market uh
participation as their 401k, they have
been excluded from buying Micro Strategy
up until now. Once Micro Strategy gets
put in, now you actually have a vehicle
by which people's passive investments
into the market will directly go into
Bitcoin via Michael Sailor converting it
onto bit, you know, Bitcoin on his
balance sheet via Micro Strategy. So,
it's a cool flywheel that has not
existed yet. It it's very exciting. Uh
it's going to it's going to create
ripples in the Bitcoin price. So for the
everyday person that's watching, they
should just look for when MSTR gets
added into S&P 500.
>> That's going to be a massive thing to
watch. Uh it should happen soon. I don't
know the exact timing of it. Um, but
when that happens, you will see billions
of dollars flow into Micro Strategy and
therefore Bitcoin due to no other reason
than like all of these passive funds
have to allocate to it now because it's
part of the S&P. I talked to Michael
Turpin in Vegas and he was telling me
about his theory, the four season theory
of Bitcoin where he thinks it is better
to buy Bitcoin in the Bitcoin winter
which is the bare market and then um
sell it in summer so then you can
accumulate more Bitcoin. That is his
theory. There are people who says never
sell your Bitcoin because you'll never
be able to buy it back. What is your
thought on these two different approach?
>> Yeah, you know what I'll say is I live
and breathe this industry I have for the
past eight years. Um I do not feel like
I know enough to time the market. Uh and
I run, you know, the largest media out
uh outlet, the the largest conference,
you know, like I if anyone wouldn't be
in the know of when it's time to buy or
sell, it would be me. And and I'm
telling you, it's so hard to to time the
market like that, but at the end of the
day, like Bitcoin is the best performing
asset in the history of mankind. Uh and
so it's it's picking up pennies in front
of a bulldozer to try and time the
market and and you know, buy in the
winter and sell in the summer. I was
looking at Google trend earlier before
we talked and Bitcoin is at very close
to all-time high but the interest on
Bitcoin is only at 25. Well, in December
2017 it was 100 and February 2022 it was
69 and right now it's only what 25.
Wh why aren't people as excited?
>> Yeah. So there's there's a couple of
things about like the intricacies of of
Google trends, right, that you'd have to
keep in mind. Number one is that uh
especially with like things like chat
GPT, right? Uh uh people actually just
aren't googling as much as they were
before, right? Uh so that's number one.
That's a small thing, right? I wouldn't
put that as a major thing. But the the
bigger thing is that um I'm guessing the
the term you're looking for is just
Bitcoin, right? People googling Bitcoin.
>> Yeah. Um, and and I would say or or what
is Bitcoin? Right? I would say that the
average person no longer needs to Google
like, "Oh, I've never heard of Bitcoin
at all, like Bitcoin." Right? Now they
have, now the questions are a little
more specific. They're like, "How do I
buy Bitcoin?" They are, uh, uh, what's a
Bitcoin ETF? Who's Michael Sailor?
What's Micro Strategy? Uh, um, you know,
why does President Trump like Bitcoin?
like uh you know like all of these kinds
of things strategic Bitcoin reserve and
so what you're seeing in my opinion is
is the market is actually starting to
learn and understand Bitcoin better and
that's what's eating into the Bitcoin
search volume more than anything. Um but
I will also at the same time say that we
are not in a mania phase. We are not in
a a crazy hype cycle mania phase like we
were in December of 2017. If you
remember December 2017, you couldn't not
talk about Bitcoin. I mean, everyone was
there. Your Uber driver wouldn't shut up
about it, right? You know, and so like
we're not at that phase right now. That
could come. I I think it will come at
some point, but you know, uh but um
we're still very early in this summer as
Michael Turpin would call it. So,
>> I love that answer. Let's talk about um
the Bitcoin theories. So, you've met a
lot of people in Bitcoin. You've
probably heard a lot of theories on
Bitcoin. Which one is your favorite? And
is there any Bitcoin related realization
that you've heard recently that you're
like, "Wow." I mean, you've been in the
industry for a long time. I can share
mine first. So, back to Michael Turpin.
He said like the last 40 years of
Bitcoin being mined, there will only be
a total of 2.5 Bitcoin being mined. And
I was like, "Oh my god." like 40 years,
2.5 bitcoins. And because it's so far
into the future, you're like, you're not
even thinking about it. So, that was my
um wow moment recently.
>> Yeah. I uh I'm looking at the total
supply right now. You know, already
we're at uh 19,900,000
Bitcoin mined. So, I mean, you know,
you're looking at
>> uh 2140 is the the year the last Bitcoin
is going to be mined. That's in uh math
is hard. Um
116 years from now, right? Uh and so in
the next 116 years, we're going to have
to mine the incremental, you know, 1.1
million Bitcoin. Um so just right there,
that should tell you all you need to
know. Like there are not a lot of
Bitcoin left to be mined. If people want
to have these type of really OG and
refreshing conversation, they can just
attend uh Bitcoin conference in Asia,
Hong Kong. Um it is coming up soon. What
can we expect?
>> So, first of all, uh I'm very excited
just to be back in and you know what we
call the east, right? Uh uh there's such
a people don't appreciate that the
original Bitcoin community was in Asia.
um you know it was not the US like in
2017 when I first joined all the action
was happening in Shanghai all the action
was happening in Japan uh in Hong Kong
all you know the the coolest startups uh
Bitmax uh uh FTX like all of these major
uh u you know three arrows like they
were all in Singapore they were all in
Hong Kong and so you know it was only
through kind of the 2021 cycle that that
shifted back you know over to the past.
Um, but it doesn't have to be that way.
And in fact, some of the most OG,
smartest whales, you know, Bitcoin
whales are still out in in, you know,
Hong Kong and Shenzhen and and Shanghai,
uh, in, you know, Tokyo and, uh, Seoul,
so on and so on. And so what I'm really
excited to do is is like this is a good
chance to bring um the the OG Bitcoin
community back together, all of the
miners up in, you know, uh the Sichuan
region of of China and everyone to to
just come back and have that one time a
year where you get to talk about
Bitcoin. You don't have to worry about
talking about all the altcoins, all the
shitcoins, all you know, no one's going
to come shill you their pro, you know,
like you just get to come talk about
Bitcoin. And and Bitcoin is the single
most interesting, most exciting thing
happening in the world today. And uh uh
and it's, you know, it's really an honor
to be able to create a platform to just
talk about it, to learn about it, to
understand what's going on today from a
technical standpoint. all of the the
stuff happening now with the treasury
companies, you know, the there's massive
stuff happening in in, you know, uh,
Hong Kong, there's Moon Inc., there's,
uh, like six different companies getting
launched in Soul right now. Obviously,
there's Metaplan in Japan. Uh, there's a
few getting launched in Thailand. It's
an amazing moment in time. Um, and and
we're in the middle of a bull market. I
mean, we're at 118k Bitcoin prices. And
so, uh, there's going to be a lot of new
faces, too. there's going to be a lot of
people that this will be their first
Bitcoin conference and so um yeah, it's
going to be a really fun time and uh you
know, we've got some amazing speakers.
We got some that we haven't announced
yet that that are uh I think going to
raise some eyebrows as well. So um yeah,
it it you can't miss it.
>> And there are really cool speakers. Eric
Trump is coming. What was the
conversation like? How do you convince
him to fly all the way to Hong Kong?
>> Yeah. Well, so you know, Eric, uh, is
someone that we've gotten to know really
well through our, you know, work with
President Trump. Um, you know, President
Trump spoke in Nashville in 2024. Uh, we
worked really closely with him on on,
you know, his Bitcoin policies, uh, that
that have now become the policy of the
government, right? Uh, and, you know,
through that process, we got to meet
Eric, we got to meet Don Jr., we got to
meet all sorts of folks kind of in his
orbit. And um what was really cool,
especially with Eric, is is he's super
knowledgeable about Bitcoin. Like he's
been in Bitcoin way longer than anyone
knows. And my first conversation, I kid
you not, my first conversation uh with
Eric was about whether he should be, you
know, uh utilizing multisig for his, you
know, company treasury or whether he
should just be sticking with a
custodian. and like what did I think
about the risk trade-off of of you know
self-custodying it and using multisig
and like what are the best practices
there and I was like dude I figured you
know we were going to talk about like
what's the difference between Bitcoin
and Ethereum and here he is like 10
steps ahead and so you know this guy's
he's truly into Bitcoin he's thought
very deeply about it you know he got
announced that he's on the advisory
board for MetaPlanet um you know he's uh
he's got a lot of knowledge and you know
He also has the ear of his father uh in
terms of making sure that like what he's
doing, what President Trump is doing is
impacting, you know, the industry in a
good way. So, um he's a very influential
person in the world right now and and
we're very excited to have him there. He
had a great time in Vegas
>> and you know, we told him we've got this
road show happening, we're going to Hong
Kong next, you know, would you want to
come? And he was like, well, I mean, you
know, is there is there a Bitcoin
community out there? And we were like,
"Oh, yeah. I mean, the the Bitcoin
community there is massive." And he was
like, "Well, I want to meet Bitcoiners
from all around the world." Uh, and, you
know, he was especially excited due to
the MetPanlet, you know, deal and and he
wanted to show up in a big way. Uh, and
and so, you know, this was the best
venue for him to to really kind of make
an appearance uh in in Hong Kong. So,
um, yeah, he's really excited about it.
I think there's going to be, you know,
some very cool um
like we we'll say path crossing that I
think will happen at the the event of
different people from, you know, the the
Hong Kong sphere uh getting to meet Eric
and vice versa. Um and you know, there
are also some other speakers, like I
said, that that uh we haven't announced
yet that I think will also uh capture
some some imagination in terms of how
those conversations might go on site.
>> So, everybody should really join us. I'm
going to go as well. You're going to go.
Um, super excited.
>> We want to end with this. An average
person in their 20s, 30s, and 40s, how
many bitcoins should they try to obtain
right now to be, let's say, a
millionaire equivalent when they reach
retirement age?
>> Yeah. So, uh, I actually have a really
funny, um, video that I did with Altcoin
Daily a few years ago, maybe a couple
years ago. um where they asked how much
Bitcoin would you need to own to be a
millionaire in the year 2032.
Um
>> and my answer was and I did the math
like on air with them. Uh and I'm not
going to go go rehash all of that, but
my answer at the time was I think 01
Bitcoin. uh and that my idea was that by
2032 it's possible that you know and
this would be like the blowoff top and
and my you know I was also hedging by
saying like I think that it would come
alongside a inflationary moment where
millionaire is not what it used to mean
right
>> but that in in in 2032
uh uh you know 01 bitcoin could get you
there potentially and and so you know is
that is that crazy bull math probably
but Uh uh what I'll say is as time goes
on, Bitcoin's value is only going to
appreciate against the dollar. I think
probably most people who are getting
into space right now uh won't ever own
one Bitcoin. That's okay. Like, you
know, it's it's just a unit, you know,
like it doesn't mean anything. Um one
Bitcoin is 100 million Satoshi's. uh you
can still own a million Satoshi's and
that's going to be a ton of value in the
future. And so, you know, it's really
just about um creating healthy financial
habits about being able to save every
day a little bit into Bitcoin and just
squirrel it away for later. Um and and
if you can have that sort of habit, like
that is that is good financial hygiene.
And Bitcoin is the best savings tool
ever created. And so if if that's your
habit, hey, I'm taking a little bit of
my paycheck and I'm putting it into
Bitcoin and I'm not touching it, then by
the time you are ready to retire, you
are going to be shocked with the the
amount of value you were able to hold on
to in that process. So that's my advice.
Um, and and you know, I I just count
myself and ourselves so lucky to be in
this moment in time where where such an
invention is like on its path. uh
because there will never be another time
like this. Uh uh it's a unique moment to
be able to actually buy Bitcoin and hold
on to it. So don't don't miss that
opportunity.
>> When you say unique, does that mean
early?
>> It means early. And frankly, it means
like there will come a time where you're
not going to be able to exchange dollars
for Bitcoin. That is not going to be a
trade that anyone is actively going to
to allow or take. What we're watching is
we're watching this thing come to
fruition
step by step every day and and like what
a cool thing. There will be history
books of history books trying to recount
and understand how this thing happened,
how Bitcoin succeeded because it is so
monumental for the history of humanity
and uh and we just happen to be the ones
living inside of it and it's so cool.
>> I love that. ending. And also people, if
people want to talk to people as cool as
Brandon, they should go grab a ticket
for Bitcoin Conference Asia. There is no
reason why you should not just check it
out, honestly.
>> Absolutely.
>> Thank you so much for your time. This
has been so much fun.
>> Yeah, it's it's been a blast. Thank you
so much for having me, buddy.